Yogesh Kumar

Fullstack Developer

Contact

yoku2010@gmail.com +91-8130935784

S vogesh kumar1988

anline resume

a offiffie resul

? yoku2010

in yoku2010

(1) yoku2010

Total Experience

9 Years and 8 Months

Skills

- proficient
 - o Python
 - JavaScript
 - o Angular
 - o ECMAScript 6
 - o TypeScript
 - o Django
 - NodeJS
 - o ExpressJS
 - ReactJS
 - Redux
 - Jest
- comfortable
 - jQuery
 - Jasmine
 - o Mocha
 - o Chai
 - HTML5CSS3
 - SASS/SCSS
 - WebpackGoogle AppsScript
- familiar
 - MongoDB
 - MySQL
 - o D3
 - Machine Learning
 - Git
 - o AWS

Languages

- native
- Hindi
- advanced
 - English

Objective

A skilled and reliable software engineer bringing in-depth experience in software development, maintenance, and the ability to work with new and existing codes. Comfortable in leading small teams, coordinating with design and marketing teams, and working with clients.

Selected Projects

PBS KIDS - Progress Tracker | Data analytical and storage system

pbskids.org

- Analytical tool to store, validate game & video events data and generate various reports.
- Research & development and made different POCs using Spark, Kibana, Logstash and Elasticsearch.
- Technical specs are Python, Django, MySQL, Cassandra, RabbitMQ, and jQuery.

PBS KIDS - Graviton | Event data analytics system

pbskids.org

- Data analytics system to store events in the database and compute various aggregate functions to generate stats for a game player.
- Technical specs are AWS Lambda Functions, DynamoDB, NodeJS, and TypeScript.

PBS KIDS - BosonJS \mid Data computation system

pbskids.org

- Realtime calculation (algorithms) on game, video & activities data and provide stats.
- Technical specs are NodeJS, ExpressJS, Angular, TypeScript, RethinkDB, Redis, and RabbitMQ.

PBS KIDS - Fascia | System monitoring tool

pbskids.org

- Monitor & administration web applications and their components.
- Technical specs are NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, Redux, ECMAScript, D3, SASS/SCSS, and MongoDB.

Shine | Online recruitment portal

shine.com

- Job seeker can register, create their profile and apply for jobs
- Recruiter can register and find best candidates.
- Technical specs are Python, Django, jQuery, MySQL, and MongoDB.

Unified Network Management Platform | Configure, manage and monitor network devices

UNMP

- Robust & scalable platform for configuring and monitoring the IP-based devices present in any enterprise or carrier-grade network.
- Search the newly installed network elements, allow to manage, group the network devices/nodes based on their location and type
- Integrate any number of devices with UNMP easily and seamlessly.
- An efficient event management system (EMS) for all the SHYAM DATA PRODUCTS.
- Technical specs are Python, Django, jQuery, MySQL, Nagios, RRDTool, SNMP, UPnP, and TCP.

Experience

08/2014 - Cont.

Excelsoft Technologies Pvt. Ltd. | Lead Engineer

Noida

- Involved in both products and services development including solution designing, product development, and documentation.
- Coding, Mentoring and helping team members by establishing processes/agendas, planning
- Interacting with clients, requirement gathering, doing daily stand-ups & following an Agile methodology.

11/2013 - 06/2014

11/2012 - 11/2013

eTouch Systems Pvt. Ltd. | Software Engineer

Gurugram

- Developed a Training Project Management System for CISCO using Python, Django AngularJS and

 MySOI
- Internal Product Release, create technical documents and coordinating daily with clients.
- HT Media Ltd. | Sr. Software Engineer
- Product development, bug fixes, performance improvement and documentation.
 Developed candidate module of shine.com using Python, Django, jQuery and MongoDB.

04/2010 -10/2012

Codescape Consultant Pvt. Ltd. | Team Lead

Jaipur

Gurugram

- Products and services development and documentation.
- Coding and Team Leading
- · Create technical documents and providing client support on-demand
- Developed web applications and network management system using Python, Django, and
 Narios
- Training delivery, Back-end, and front-end development.

Education

2009 B.E./B.Tech | Information Technology

University of Rajasthan

- Studied Algorithm, Computer languages, Operating System and Data Structure.
- From Govt. Engineering College, Ajmer with 65.15% marks.

2005 **12th** | *Science & Maths*

RBSE

- Studied Physics Chemistry and Mathematics.
- From D.A.V. Senior Secondary School, Ajmer (Rajasthan Board of Secondary Education) with 60.77% marks.